ANAND PATIDAR

Business Development Manager

anandz2a@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/anand-patidar-74b9711a0 • Ahmedabad

Summary

I am a dedicated Business Development Manager with over 4 years of experience in high-ticket sales, management, and event planning. I excel in creating effective strategies to drive revenue, surpassing sales targets, and fostering strong client relationships. My background includes managing diverse teams in fast-paced environments, ensuring successful outcomes through team-building and communication.

Key Achievements

Sales Growth Achieved

Increased monthly sales by 25% through strategic planning and execution.

Exceeded Sales Targets

Exceeded quarterly sales targets by 20% consistently over one-year period.

Customer Retention Boost

Implemented CRM system, boosting customer retention rate by 15% in six months.

Market Expansion Success

Expanded market territory by 30% in one year through targeted marketing.

Experience

Egniol Group of Companies

02/2023 - Present

Ahmedabad

Business Development Manager

A business group specializing in various business operations focused on growth and development.

- Created effective marketing, sales and promotional initiatives to drive revenue.
- · Created short-term and long-term goals for business team to achieve objectives.
- · Planned and developed winning strategies to increase sales, expand territories and boost market positioning.
- Surpassed sales and customer service targets, consistently exceeding established KPIs.
- Identified cross-selling opportunities through ongoing customer needs analysis.
- Closed long-term agreements through skilful negotiation.

LIGMR (Egniol Group Of Companies)

Ahmedabad

International Business Manager

02/2024 - Present

A well reputed management institute based in Lyon, France focusing on Quality education and opening doors for global opportunities.

- Implemented strategies that boosted global market share.
- · Fostered partnerships to drive business growth.
- Built high-performing teams to surpass objectives consistently.
- Mentored senior staff, fostering a strong leadership team.
- Cultivated robust industry alliances to enhance service promotion.
- Negotiated international contracts, securing favorable terms and building strong partnerships with overseas clients.

BYJU's the Learning Application

Indore

Senior Business Development Associate

02/2021 - 12/2022

A leading ed-tech company providing learning solutions through innovative learning platforms.

- Engaged with customers to proactively schedule and confirm sales meetings.
- Generated revenue and established customer networks for potential business.
- Built and managed a tracking system to analyze the team member's scheduled meetings, revenue generated, and finance data.
- Established more ideas to create an easy, flexible, approachable method and strategy to boost the team's performance.
- Guided the team to achieve the weekly target above 80%.
- Took responsibility to cover the deficit revenue and guided new team members for generating maximum sales and creating a proper sales funnel.

Hututu Softwares Indore

Trainee 01/2020 - 05/2020

A software company focusing on delivering effective software solutions.

- Reported back to the instructor to receive day-to-day tasks and responsibilities.
- · Learned new materials, processes, and programs quickly.
- Completed documentation and reports for business records.
- · Experience with management of project documentation, compressing project design and documenting application.

Powered by CY Enhancy

Education

Shri Vaishnav Vidyapeeth Vishwavidyalaya Bachelor in Technology Indore, MP 08/2016 - 05/2020

Languages

English Proficient •••• Hindi Proficient ••••

Skills

 $Business\ Development \cdot CRM \cdot Strategic\ Planning \cdot Market\ Research \cdot Relationship\ Building \cdot Lead\ Generation \cdot Team\ Building$

Interests

+ Cricket + Music + Football